<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Etl on Codes are a puzzle</title>
    <link>https://iqnev.github.io/tags/etl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Etl on Codes are a puzzle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://iqnev.github.io/tags/etl/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Core Features and Components of Apache Camel</title>
      <link>https://iqnev.github.io/posts/exploring_core_features_and_components_of_apache_camel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iqnev.github.io/posts/exploring_core_features_and_components_of_apache_camel/</guid>
      <description>Hello friends! In our previous discussion, we delved into the integration of Apache Camel with Quarkus, demonstrating how to craft real-world applications using Apache Camel. As we continue our series, we aim to take a deep dive into the crucial components and the intrinsic details of Apache Camel.&#xA;Enterprise Integration Patterns At its core, Apache Camel is structured around the concepts introduced in the Enterprise Integration Patterns (EIP) book by Gregor Hohpe and Bobby Woolf.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practical Guide to Apache Camel with Quarkus: Building an ETL Application</title>
      <link>https://iqnev.github.io/posts/practical_guide_to_apache_camel_with_quarkus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iqnev.github.io/posts/practical_guide_to_apache_camel_with_quarkus/</guid>
      <description>I am excited to introduce a series of articles about Apache Camel. In this first post, rather than delving deeply into the complexities of Apache Camel, I will present a practical use case to showcase its capabilities. Specifically, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to create a simple Extract, Transform, and Load (ETL) application between two databases using Apache Camel.&#xA;Introduction to Apache Camel - Brief Overview Before we dive into the practical use case, let&amp;rsquo;s briefly introduce Apache Camel.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
